So we'll just restart the server with the run command and refresh. And we have rails
eight basic auth. And we can see that there's some tailwind CSS
Giving it a little bit of styling.
Now, a quick look at what we've generated is a standard controller called home with
index. We're skipping routes because we want to use the route for this, and we can
see just a slight modification to the routes. And here's the HTML that's going on.
So we've got this in place here a standard view has been created and we've got a
couple of specs. So we've got this home helper. We've got a request spec and we've
got this view spec. Now I'm going to get rid of the view specs.
but request specs we will look at, especially when we're doing the authentication.
Now I'll just bring the terminal into focus. I'm running guard and we'll run the
tests. And we've got one that's just been skipped, and we've got one that's in error.
the one that's being skipped, which is a helper I'm also going to remove. And let's
have a look at the request spec.
you can see here that it's home slash index. Now I've gone and changed the route
so that the home index will point to the route. So let's just make sure we change
it here and we'll hit save.
And now we have a working request spec for the root.
Let's now play around with the layout. We'll get a menu in place for the authentication
system. We'll also look at alert messages. So we have all this code going on for
the different menus that we want to do. We've got a little bit of changes to the
layout, especially adding in the menu.
in the next step we'll work with the flash messages where they'll just use tailwind
CSS to style them.
We'll head over to the web,
firstly run the layout and we'll just see how things change with that.
this time for the flash messages, which is number four.
if we come and do a refresh, we can see the layout in place. The flash messages will
show up a bit later.
one of the things I was encountering is that the asset precompilation doesn't happen
automatically, and there should be a little bit of styling here.
rerun the web server. It's also going to do the asset precompile.
if we do a refresh we get a new look and feel.
Next I want to generate a few controller pages, but before I do that, I'm going to
modify a few of the settings going on here, and then we'll add in the pages and the
controllers here.
I want to generate three top level pages for the authentication system. But before
we do that, I would like to play around with the configuration of the generator.
So we'll make these changes followed by the generation of the pages.
we can firstly do the application settings,
we'll restart the generator and we'll do the top level pages. Number six.
now we've got our pages controller. There's three actions ready to go. If we look
in the views, we've got some pages being pre-created for us.
We've also got the shared information from the flash messages and the menus that
we just created earlier. If we look down at the unit tests,
You'll see that it's now only generating the request spec. So if we click on that,
there should be three in place ready to go.
Let's just head over to the terminal and put in a guard, and we'll see if these three
request specs are running okay. They are,
come over to the web view and we refresh and we can see there's now three pages available.
you see any styling issues, just restart the server. I know that this should be a
darker color.
if we click on them, we should be able to go to the three different pages that we
want to test with the security system.