Now the next step is to create a bunch of authentication enhancements, especially
registration, the view and links. So what we'll do is we'll find number nine
So let's come and have a look at the changes. If we go into configuration, we can
see there's a change to the routes, and we didn't look at some of the routes from
earlier as well. So we've got the resource registration session and passwords in
place. We've also got
three pages that we added earlier. If we come up to application and look within models,
there's a modification to the user. So we've now got validation going on on the email
address.
A new registrations page has been created,
and a new registration link has been added to the session.
So now we'll be able to register a new user.
we have the registrations controller. There's a new and a create method here. And
if we have a brief look on the application controller, we can see now there's a current
user that we can access
let's test the register. We'll click on here and we'll put in appydave@appydave.com.
click Register.
it has registered successfully. I don't know that we'll be able to sign in yet. Let's
just try that. So we appear to be signed in, but we got no information about the
user.
I would like to put that on the authentication page.
Now to visualize the user we'll press number ten which is authentication information.
We've got a new page. If we do a refresh we now have the idea of what the user is.
But there's something missing here because you would have noticed that we did register.
So to give a little bit of clarity around this authentication model, what we have
done is allow unauthenticated access. So it's basically skipping the require action.
And we can see that going on here. It said for authentication page we don't need
to be authenticated. But that doesn't mean you've got access to the authentication
information. And the authentication information we're interested in is here in the
current session which is looking in the session store. So we need to call this resume
session. So what we can do is come back here and just say before action resume session
for that particular page. Now we'll hit save on that. Come back to the authentication
details and we'll refresh.
now that user that we registered appydave@appydave.com is visible.
a recompile of the assets is giving us the sign out button. Let's see if that's working.
We'll click on it.
Let's try and sign back in appydave@appydave.com we'll click sign in. We'll click
on the authentication page. And there we have it.
Let's now see if we can add email validation to the sign up process. So we'll go
to the register user.
to try with appydave2. Now before we run that we're going to
authentication email.
what we've done is add a new table to the database.
So the main changes are that the confirmation token and confirmed that have been
added to the users. And then after that we've got some extra methods, plus the ability
to send an email and regenerate a token.
Additionally, we've got the registrations. Controller now has a confirm button on
it. We've got a user mailer with the ability to take the email. If we go into routes,
we've got letter opener because that's been added via the gem.
an important thing to think about is with the configuration, the default URL options
change it to the same port as whatever your web server is running on. So let's go
test it out.
Now we're back at the registration where we've got AP Dave two. We'll click Register
and it looks like it's come up with an email system. Let's click on this. Confirm
the account.
we are now confirmed. So we should be able to sign in with that. There's now also
a check email. If we click on that that'll take us over to letter opener. Now we
don't need to do that because we've already done it using the default viewer. But
if we go and click on the authentication page, it won't say that we're signed in
just yet. So let's just click on the sign in and we'll put in appydave2 And we'll
do that one more time.
now we can get to the account page which wasn't available before. If we look at the
authentication page we can see that we're signed in correctly.
I'm AppyDave Please like and subscribe and I'll see you in the next video.