the next step is to generate the new authentication system that comes with rails
eight. Now we could run step number seven which would do the rails generate authentication
and update the database. But let's have a look at this manually. So firstly I'm just
going to run rails generate authentication.
we can see the new files come in. Now notice there's also an update database. If
we go and have a look at what that's really doing. It's just a rails DB migrate and
a rails DB test prepare. So let's run them manually as well. So just running the
rails db migrate to update the database. The test prepare will make sure that the
test database is in sync as well.
heading over to the application, let's have a look at what's changed. So if we go
into the database migrations we can see there's a new table being added called users.
It's got an email address and a password digest. After that we've got the sessions
for each time a user signs in with just their IP address and user agent.
heading over to the app folder. There's a lot of changes going on here.
we'll look at the views. We've got the passwords, email and new. There's also a mailer.
So when we send out an email for resets that'll be there.
we've also got the new sessions view going on here.
everything's been done using tailwind CSS.
A simple little mailer has been created for resetting the password, and then we start
looking at the data going on with the models. So the first one would be the user
it's got has secure password and has many sessions. It's also down casing the email
address. Then after that we've got the session which is belonging to a user. And
if you want to access the current user in session, we've got this current attribute
set up with the session and a delegation through to the user. Let's now go have a
look at the controller, where a lot of extra work is happening in the passwords controller
and the session controller.
Now you can see on the passwords controller. This allowed unauthenticated access
and if we go to sessions, it's also got the same thing set up for the new and the
create action here. And to find that we can go to the application controller where
it's including a concept called authentication. And this is a new concern being built
here.
so the bulk of the code going on for the authentication system can be found in this
concern.
Now let's go and see how this is affecting the web application. So we've got the
authentication concern. It's now included automatically on the application controller.
And both the home controller and the pages controller have been left the way they
are now if we head over to the website and this is what we saw before, if I do a
refresh, we now get taken to a sign in page.
should be happening for everything.
So let's start by just putting in a username and password. We haven't registered
it yet and we'll see what happens.
Now we get to see a valid error message coming up here. But the other good thing
is the alert message that we styled with tailwind CSS earlier is now coming through.
I want to relax some of the security, the home and the about page don't need to be
locked down. The account page does, and the authentication page should show information
about whether the user is signed in or not.
So I'm pressing number eight for relax.
we can see there's a change to the home controller and the pages controller. If we
do a refresh and the home page now allows us through, let's go have a look at what's
going on in the pages controller. So the home controller has allow unauthenticated
access, which is why we were able to get to that page with the pages controller.
We've got this concept of allow unauthenticated access only for two of the particular
pages. So let's just save that and we'll see what happens if we click on the about
and the authentication there. Good. And we're still locked down for the account.