In this video, we're setting up rails eight with the new basic authentication system
also include tailwind CSS, Postgres guard for automated test watching, R-spec and
Rubocop.
Now let's get started by being on the latest version of Ruby and Rails. So with Ruby,
I'm currently on 3.3.6. Now to install rails, I'll just run gem install rails
That's finished. And we've installed rails 8.00.0.
Now there's a setup guide that you can follow through, but what we've done so far
is check the version of Ruby and install the latest version of rails. What we'll
do now is just set up a repository that you can find this code in.
Now I'm just over at GitHub on AppyDave. We'll create a new repository inside of
this. We'll call it rails8-basicauth. Now we're going to make it public.
we'll set the license to the Mozilla Public License two.
And a basic description. Let's just create this repository.
So the command we're going to start off with is rails new rails eight basic auth.
We're not going to include any test frameworks because we're going to use RSpec.
We will include tailwind CSS and Postgres as the database.
Heading over to the terminal, we'll paste in that command and let it do the standard
rails creation process.
Now the new application is finishing creating. What we're going to need to do is
change into the directory. And because we're using Postgres we'll need to create
the database. So let's just CD into the correct folder. We'll clear the screen here
and we'll do a rails DB create. And that should just create the databases rails eight
basic auth development and test.
Now let's just test whether the server is running. We've got Chrome open, we're starting
up the web server and we'll run it. And we're running rails eight with rack 3.1.8
and Ruby 3.3.6.
Now let's connect this repo up to the repo we've already created on GitHub. So we'll
just put this information in right now. And then let's just run the add dot, commit
the initial request and push it all up. So we'll let that go. And that's all moving.
And we'll come over to the repo and just refresh. And we've got the initial commit.
So as we go along I'll be doing commit along the way. And you can go to any section
that you like.
Now for a little bit of basic setup. We're just going to make sure that everything
that we do is done in a template, that you can just run from the command line. So
we'll just go and create this file. We've created it, we've touched it. And lastly
we'll also put in the setup documentation that we're reading through at the moment.
So this will all be in the repository.
Now we have a standard rails application created with tailwind, CSS and Postgres.
Now what I've added is a rails generator that you can use, and it's just a standard
rails generator with a bunch of steps that we're running through. And as we go through
them, they'll just be called by different numbers so that you can cherry pick what
you want to do with the generation of this application.
I'll just take you through a couple of aliases I've set up, the main one being the
R8. Next is how we'll go through each capability of the rails eight application.
there's also a run command, which will run the rails server with a precompile in
front of it. So what we'll do is just paste all of this and it's now available. Now
we can test that out by typing run. And it should just do a standard rails server
with Precompile.
Now let's just quickly look at this template command that we've set up. There's a
file. We'll look at it in a moment. Some of the information came from prior documentation
that I read a month ago on the pre-releases of rails eight. But if we go to the top,
we're using rails generators as a base class, and then a bunch of classes for each
So what we're going to work through is creating common gems. A home page will do
the layout. We'll get some alert messages
and also adding an email authentication mailer to the system.
run our little command line tool. Right? Next we'll get a menu and we're going to
work with number one. What that'll do is add the various gems and start doing a bundle
install. There's also a bundle outdated going on and it actually finishes off with
a Rubocop dash A. So any issues in the code base will be cleaned up.
Now let's have a quick look at what's changed. Firstly, if we go to the Gemfile,
we can have a look at the original files that have been added. We've got rails eight,
we've got a Postgres gem. These are the new concepts that I'm going to talk about
in a future video around solid cache, queue and cable.
additionally it's also added in the information I want for the custom gems. If we
look at the spec file, it's set up with a require spec helper, and I like to use
the documentation format. If we go into spec, there's a rails helper and a spec helper
already preset up and a guard file. And what the guard
is watching our rails application. If we run it, nothing's happening at the moment.
Now just label this commit. And what that means is that when you come up to the repo,
you should be able to just look through and find the areas that have been changed
labeled in the repo.
Now that I've got the basic gems set up, I'd like to get a home page going. Now you
can see that I'm running a rails server. It's on port 3001 and if we run rate next,
it will be looking for the template file in the public directory called rails template.
So we'll just run number two.
what that's going to do is create the controller and the home page to get started.